Best Friend Forever* (*battery life may vary)
Ron's Gone Wrong is a animation, science fiction,
family film directed by Sarah Smith.
In a world where walking, talking, digitally connected bots have become children's best friends, an
11-year-old finds that his robot buddy doesn't quite work the same as the others do.
Barney (voice), played by Jack Dylan Grazer.
Ron (voice), played by Zach Galifianakis.
Graham (voice), played by Ed Helms.
Donka (voice), played by Olivia Colman.
Andrew (voice), played by Rob Delaney.
Marc (voice), played by Justice Smith.
Ron's Gone Wrong is a 2021 animated science fiction comedy film directed by Sarah
Smith and Jean-Philippe Vine, and written by Smith and Peter Baynham.
The voice cast features Jack Dylan Grazer, Zach Galifianakis, Ed Helms, Justice
Smith, Rob Delaney, Kylie Cantrall, Ricardo Hurtado, and Olivia Colman.
The film follows Barney, a socially awkward middle-schooler who, after the release of a
popular line of robots, receives and befriends a defective robot he names Ron.
Ron's Gone Wrong was the first feature film from Locksmith
Animation, and was animated by DNEG Animation.
Animation and voice acting for the film were all done
remotely during the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film had its world premiere at the 65th BFI London Film Festival on 9 October 2021, and was theatrically released
in the United Kingdom on 15 October, and in the United States on 22 October, by 20th Century Studios.
The film grossed $60.7 million and received
generally positive reviews from critics.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.